This chronic back pain has been one of
the biggest challenges of my life. This
experience where this pain at such a
pivotal cornerstone piece of your body
is tied into every movement. There's no
escaping it. Psychologically,
physically, emotionally, it has been
such a difficult experience and given me
so much sympathy for people in chronic
pain. If you have not been in serious
chronic pain, it is impossible to
understand what it's like until you're
there. And I would say the one mantra of
sorts that has allowed me to start
digging out of that hole, and I use a
different term for myself. I don't
remember where I got it, but it was just
like scale it down. Absolutely. I might
need this surgery in the elbow. Okay,
great. I can't do X number of push-ups.
Okay, fine. Do 1/10 of X number of
push-ups. But the rule is you can't do
nothing. You have to scale it down. And
maybe you omit exercises, sure. But it's
like train around it, train around it,
train around it. For instance, the box
squat. Great example. Jersey Gregoreck,
who I keep mentioning, is the ultimate
master of regressions. To use your word,
because he'll have someone they'll do a
squat and they'll go down 8 in and he's
like, "That's it." And they're like,
"No, but I do a little parallel in the
gym." And he's like, "You shouldn't."
And he's just like, "Okay, your max
depth is whatever." I'm making this
number up, but it's like 36 in off the
ground. And they're like, "That's a
joke." And he's like, "That's your
assignment." And it feels like a waste
of time to start off in where he would
start people. But as they develop the
right mechanics and then pain-free
progress, and it takes weeks maybe even
months to get back to where they think
they should be. And then lo and behold,
they are so much stronger. They own the
position. All these aches and pains go
away. You can't do nothing, but you can
scale it down or regress it, right?